Dobato, what are you doing?
Making decorations out of this pretty paper!
If I remember correctly, those
papers are from the landlady's...
Yes! Chitose received a lot as a present from the bookstore,
so she told me to give it to the Nursery.
I'll make a lot of decorations like this and hang them on the walls and windows!
Do you think they will like it?
They'll probably be annoyed, actually.
Let me give you some advice.
What you have there is called origami paper.
Normally, you play with it by folding it!
W-What should I do, Ioryogi?
I can't... I can't make it go back!
Ioryogi!
Obviously...
There's no way to undo what you did!
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday,
your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...Concealed Prayer.
Thank you.
Miss Sayaka.
Hm?
You didn't get very much sleep, did you?
I can tell from your face.
Now see here.
You can't go around saying such things about women's faces!
You'll hurt their feelings.
That wasn't a joke—!
I'll bring this to the office.
Please and thank you!
U-Um... Miss Sayaka?
Ah, Kobato.
I-I'm sorry!
What on earth are you apologizing for?
Chitose said to give this to everyone at the Nursery.
Oh, it's origami paper.
And so much of it too!
Actually, there was even more than that,
but I didn't know origami paper was supposed to be folded
and I did something I shouldn't have...
I'm so sorry!
Miss Sayaka?
Miss Sayaka!
Fujimoto!
Fujimoto!!
What?
Miss Sayaka is—
I'm fine.
Let's get you to a hospital immediately.
I'm fine, really.
There's no way you could be fine after collapsing like that!
Really. If I just rest for a bit...
I'll be fine.
If you'd rather see a doctor, I know one!
I'll go get him immediately!
Kobato?
Kobato! Where are you going?
Excuse me!
Hello?
Please open the door!
Is anyone there?
Kobato?
What's the matter?
Is Shuichiro here?
Please help me! Miss Sayaka is—!
Please!
What's the matter with Miss Sayaka?
Nothing you guys need to worry about.
How is she?
She's fatigued from lack of sleep and has a light case of gastric inflammation.
I see.
I'll prescribe medicine for her.
After she rests and settles down, have her eat something easily digestible.
Yes.
Sorry for bothering you so suddenly.
Don't worry about it. I'm glad I happened to be on break.
U-Um...
Is Miss Sayaka okay?
If she continues to go on like this,
it won't be long before her condition is much worse than just collapsing.
It'd be a good idea not to
think of this as just fatigue.
Please tell this to her too.
Right.
Well then, take care.
Thank you very much.
How do you know him?
Huh?
That doctor.
He lives together with Kohaku...
Kohaku?
Oh, the one from last time...
Yes.
What's the matter?
Um... Is Miss Sayaka sick?
She's okay.
Really?
Really.
She'll get better soon. Even the doctor said so.
If you guys go around acting all upset,
Miss Sayaka will get worried, won't she?
Let's all sing together energetically and help Miss Sayaka get better, okay?
Yeah!
Underneath the blue, blue sky,
That Kobato, she completely forgot about me.
in the valley...
Hey.
Y-Yes?
If you silently stay by her side like that,
do you think Miss Sayaka will get better?
But... just a little longer...
Stop it.
Instead of doing this, wouldn't
taking good care of the children
let Miss Sayaka rest much more easily?
I suppose you're right...
How was the patient?
She's settled down.
I see.
I'm glad.
If you do this... then this...
You get a samurai's attendant!
I see!
So that's how you play with origami.
Look here, look here, Kobato!
Wow!
A balloon?
What are you folding over there, Toshihiko?
Cranes!
Cranes?
They're a type of bird.
Oh, it's a bird!
You're folding a lot of them, aren't you?
Yeah. A thousand of them!
What?
A thousand?
Yup. So Miss Sayaka will hurry up and get better.
If you fold a thousand cranes, you can make sick people get better.
Toshihiko!
Please teach me how to fold cranes too!
I'll fold cranes too!
Me too!
Then let's all fold cranes together!
Like... like this?
Like this, see...
Ah...
It's difficult, isn't it...
So it's like that...
Ah, you did it!
You did it!
Do you think she'll be okay?
Kobato, I mean.
You're worrying about the wrong person, aren't you?
Ah, really?
I suppose you're right.
But... I don't know why, but I'm concerned for Kobato.
Will Miss Sayaka be better tomorrow?
Everything'll be okay!
We managed to fold a thousand cranes after all!
Yeah!
All right... I'll try to come back from work as soon as I can,
but I'll be counting on you to take care of Miss Sayaka.
Okay.
If anything happens, contact me immediately.
Manager, there's a favor I want to ask of you...
What's up? Why the formality?
I was wondering if I could have less hours for a little while.
Hm?
Don't you need money?
I do, but...
Right now, there's something more important...
I got it.
In exchange, I'm gonna work you hard when you're free again!
I apologize for this.
Thank you.
Miss Sayaka.
Kobato?
Have you been watching over me this whole time?
Yes.
What about the children?
Their parents have all come to pick them up and everyone's gone home now.
I see.
I'm sorry for worrying you like this.
Please keep resting!
I was planning on putting up a good fight too...
Huh?
But then you showed up to help out...
And with both you and Fujimoto here, I suppose I felt at ease
and thought that it would be okay to just leave things to the two of you...
If something does end up happening to me...
Why would you say that?
Why... would you...
If something were to ever
happen to you, Miss Sayaka...
Everyone would be so sad.
That's why... That's why you
absolutely talk like that!
Kobato.
Things are done here for today. Go home.
Huh?
You're already a space case.
If you were to get even more
spaced out due to a lack of sleep,
I'd be in trouble, wouldn't I?
Space case?
I'm not a space case!
I'll take over for you from here, so go home.
Okay.
You're no help to anyone if your mind is somewhere else.
I said I'm not—
Hurry up and get going.
She scolded me.
What she said was right.
I know.
Things really are as she said.
The kids all worked together to fold those.
I see.
Here are the ones she made.
The ones over here are all like this.
She's such a good kid, isn't she?
Yeah.
The Six Major Laws
Are you really that worried about Sayaka?
Hey, Kobato.
Huh?
No, nothing.
Okay.
Could it be that her lost memories have returned?
Hanamaro
Drill
I did
it!
So much
fun!
Japanese
Chiho.
What's the answer to number seven?
Oh no! You don't know either, Chise?
Oh?
Kobato!
It's Kobato!
Is Chitose here?
Mama's at the neighborhood
association meeting right now.
I see.
What's the matter?
You look down, Kobato.
To tell you the truth... it's an illness!
Oh no, Kobato!
N-Not me!
Huh?
It's Miss Sayaka who's sick.
I want to do something to help Miss
Sayaka, but I don't know what I should do.
We see, we see.
I helped to fold a thousand cranes along with the kids at the Nursery, but...
A thousand cranes!
Yes.
But I wasn't really good at folding them...
What if our wish isn't able to come true because of my badly folded cranes?
Don't worry, Kobato!
I'm sure your wish will come true, Kobato!
I really hope so...
Oh! What about that thing?
Huh?
You know, the thing that Mama
always makes for us when we get sick!
Um...rice porridge?
Yes, rice porridge!
I get it! Rice porridge!
Huh?
Mama said rice porridge is easy to digest so it's easy on your stomach when you're sick.
Easy to digest?
Shuichiro said the same thing!
He said to have Miss Sayaka eat something easily digestible!
In that case, why don't you make some rice porridge for her?
I'm sure it'll help Miss Sayaka get better!
Yes! I'll make some rice porridge for Miss Sayaka!
But how should I make that...
How about we draw a picture for her, Chiho?
Good idea, Chise!
It's something like this...
So this is rice porridge!
It's white...
And kind of gooey!
Right!
G-o-o-e-y!
Gooey
Mama said you'll burn yourself if
you're not careful when you eat i!
H-o-t!
And when you make it, you add lots and lots of water!
D-r-e-n-c-h!
Is this really going to turn out okay?
Who's there?!
What are you doing?
I was trying to make rice porridge...
Drench
White
Easy to digest
Gooey
How to Make Rice Porridge
Lid
Hot
I had Chiho and Chise go through the trouble of teaching me,
but I can't get it right...
Rice porridge is supposedly easy to digest.
That's why I thought I'd make some for Miss Sayaka...
After you put in the rice, add in plenty of water.
Then wait until it mixes all
together and comes to a boil.
After that, simmer it for a bit on a low fire and you're done.
Seriously, how did you brew up that concoction?
If you made someone eat that, even an illness that was about to get better would just get worse.
Hey. Don't cry.
If Miss Sayaka dies...
It'll be fine. People don't die that easily.
Some do!
Some people really do die just
because of some tiny, little thing.
Did that happen to someone?
It'll be okay.
Miss Sayaka won't die.
Delicious!
I'll be healthy in no time!
Thank goodness.
I feel like I might even overeat.
It's really good!
I'm happy that I could be of help to you.
I was the one who did just about everything.
T-That's true... but...
But what?
Nothing.
Exactly.
You haven't gotten any.
Huh?
Staring at them like that
won't create more konpeito.
I know!
Huh?
You seem rather happy after hearing that.
Speaking of which...
I wonder why...
Hm?
At that time, when I just broke
down and cried in front of Fujimoto,
something heavy that had been twisted up inside of me seemed to come loose and...
Turned into an extremely warm feeling.
You're the one who's supposed to be healing people, but instead, you get healed yourself.
What are we going to do with you?
I... was healed?
This is...
Good morning.
Good morning!
Morning.
It's Miss Sayaka!
Good morning!
Good morning, Miss Sayaka!
Good morning.
Are you all better now, Miss Sayaka?
I'm all right now.
Our thousand cranes must have worked!
Good morning, Kobato!
Good morning!
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...Mysterious Lifeform.